Guide to the Stanford University, J. Henry Meyer Memorial Library, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, J. Henry Meyer Memorial Library, records
1957-2006
SC0703
Stanford University. Libraries. J. Henry Meyer Memorial Library.
18 Linear feet
Records include architectural design documents, 1957-66 and 1988; Meyer Council Minutes, 1968-86; administrative files on the catalog as well as bound copies of the catalog; records from library instruction activities, 1966-83, including papers from a course on the undergraduate library taught by Jack Plotkin, 1962-64; other administrative files; photograph album on staff, 1966-74; and materials from 40th anniversary celebration in 2006.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Records include architectural design documents, 1957-66 and 1988; Meyer Council Minutes, 1968-86; administrative files on the catalog as well as bound copies of the catalog; records from library instruction activities, 1966-83, including papers from a course on the undergraduate library taught by Jack Plotkin, 1962-64; other administrative files; photograph album on staff, 1966-74; and materials from 40th anniversary celebration in 2006.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Libraries. J. Henry Meyer Memorial Library.; Stanford University. Libraries.; Academic libraries --California.; Libraries--California.; Library orientation for college students.
Collection Contents
- Architectural plans and specifications; Meyer Council minutes, Accession ARCH-1988-066
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2001-064
- 40th Anniversary Records, Accession ARCH-2007-014
  - Undergraduate library project, 1963-65 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Furniture and equipment 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Furniture and equipment 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Furniture and equipment 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, outside of building (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dedication, correspondence and photographs, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Master building specs, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Master building specs, with changes, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Architects – summary and drawings [ca. 1987], circa 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - [Architects – transparencies, ca. 1987], circa 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Articles, clippings, etc., 1965-98 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meyer articles 1987-89 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Annual reports, 1967-79 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Annual reports, 1980-90 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Meyer catalog – history, specs, and generalities, 1963-78 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meyer catalog – filing specs (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Language Lab – historical 1965-85 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Language Lab/Meyer merger 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meyer Program Renewal – early beginnings to 6/30/85 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Meyer Program Renewal summary 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Smoking 1966-67, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous re staff 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Copies of documents re Meyer history (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Photos: baseball game, staff v. students 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Photos: 2 staff members (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photos: staff parties (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photos: Meyer party 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photos: miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photo album of Meyer staff 1966-74 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Report on Future Meyer Program, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Timothy Portwood, Patton speech, 2006 Nov 16; 1 computer file(s) (MP3)
  - Videorecording, 2006; 1 computer file(s) (MP4)
  - Stewart Brand at Meyer's 40th Anniversary, 12/1/2006; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 40th anniversary flyers, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Digital printouts of photos (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Photographs
    - Portwood, Timothy, 4 computer file(s) (TIFF)